Register of the John R. Chaisson Papers, 1940-1975.
Hoover Institution Archives
- Letters to Mrs. John R. Chaisson, 1948-1968. (Box No. 2-7.)
  - April 16, 1967, Saigon
  - April 18, 1967, Saigon
  - April 22, 1967, Saigon
  - April 24, 1967, Saigon
  - April 25, 1967, Saigon
  - April 27, 1967, Saigon
  - April 28, 1967, Saigon
  - April 29, 1967, Saigon
  - April 30, 1967, Saigon
  - May 2, 1967, Saigon
  - May 6, 1967, Saigon
  - May 10, 1967, Saigon
  - May 11, 1967, Saigon
  - May 15, 1967, Saigon
  - May 16, 1967, Saigon
  - May 20, 1967, Saigon
  - May 25, 1967, Saigon
  - May 27, 1967, Saigon
  - June 4, 1967, Saigon
  - June 12, 1967, Saigon
  - June 18, 1967, Saigon
  - June 20, 1967, Saigon
  - June 21, 1967, Saigon
  - June 22, 1967, Saigon
  - June 23, 1967, Saigon
  - June 27, 1967, Saigon
  - July 1, 1967, Saigon (Box 7.)
  - July 4, 1967, Saigon
  - July 6, 1967, Saigon
  - July 7, 1967, Saigon
  - July 10, 1967, Saigon
  - July 12, 1967, Saigon
  - July 13, 1967, Saigon
  - July 17, 1967, Saigon
  - August 14, 1967, Saigon
  - August 16, 1967, Saigon
  - August 19, 1967, Saigon
  - August 20, 1967, Saigon
  - August 28, 1967, Saigon
  - September 4, 1967, Saigon
  - September 6, 1967, Saigon
  - September 7, 1967, Saigon
  - September 10, 1967, Saigon
  - September 14, 1967, Saigon
  - September 16, 1967, Saigon
  - September 24, 1967, Saigon
  - September 24, 1967, Saigon
  - September 30, 1967, Saigon
  - October 5, 1967, Sagion
  - October 8, 1967, Saigon
  - October 9, 1967, Saigon
  - October 12, 1967, Saigon
  - October 14, 1967, Saigon
  - October 17, 1967, Saigon
  - October 22, 1967, Saigon
  - October 26, 1967, Saigon
  - October 31, 1967, Saigon
  - November 4, 1967, Saigon
  - November 5, 1967, Saigon
  - November 7, 1967, Saigon
  - November 12, 1967, Saigon
  - November 14, 1967, Saigon
  - November 17, 1967, Saigon
  - November 18, 1967, enroute to New Delhi
  - November 18, 1967, New Delhi
  - November 21, 1967, New Delhi
  - November 22, 1967, enroute to Saigon
  - November 25, 1967, Saigon
  - November 29, 1967, Saigon
  - November 30, 1967, Saigon
  - December 2, 1967, Saigon
  - December 6, 1967, Saigon
  - December 11, 1967, Saigon
  - December 17, 1967, Saigon
  - January 23, 1968, Guam
  - January 24, 1968, Saigon
  - January 28, 1968, Saigon
  - February 1, 1968, Saigon
  - February 2, 1968, Saigon
  - February 6, 1968, Saigon
  - February 8, 1968, Saigon
  - February 11, 1968, Saigon
  - February 14, 1968, Saigon
  - February 15, 1968, Saigon
  - February 18, 1968, Saigon
  - February 20, 1968, Saigon
  - February 28, 1968, Saigon
  - February 29, 1968, Saigon
  - March 2, 1968, Saigon
  - March 8, 1968, Saigon
  - March 14, 1968, Saigon
  - March 16, 1968, Saigon
  - March 18, 1968, Saigon
  - March 22, 1968, Saigon
  - March 23, 1968, Saigon
  - March 28, 1968, Saigon
  - March 30, 1968, Saigon
  - April 3, 1968, Saigon
  - April 6, 1968, Saigon
  - April 8, 1968, Saigon
  - April 13, 1968, Saigon
  - April 17, 1968, Saigon
  - April 19, 1968, Saigon
  - April 21, 1968, Saigon
  - April 24, 1968, Saigon
  - April 24, 1968, Saigon
  - April 28, 1968, Saigon
  - May 2, 1968, Saigon
  - May 6, 1968, Saigon
  - May 14, 1968, Saigon
  - May 16, 1968, Saigon
  - May 21, 1968, Saigon
  - May 28, 1968, Saigon
  - June 2, 1968, Saigon
  - June 4, 1968, Saigon
- Diaries and Appointment Books, 1942-1972. (Box No. 7-10.)
  Diaries and appointment books, arranged chronologically.
  - Diaries, 1942-1968 (Box 7.)
    - March 17 - October 11, 1942
    - December 30, 1965 - December 31, 1966
    - December 1-30, 1966
    - January 1-31, 1967
    - January 1 - May 23, 1967 (Box 8.)
    - February 1-28, 1967
    - March 1-31, 1967
    - March 25 - April 7, 1967
    - April 6-12, 1967
    - April 14 - May 6, 1967
    - April 20-29, 1967
    - May 7 - June 8, 1967
    - May 8-14, 1967
    - May 15-24, 1967
    - May 24 - July 26, 1967
    - May 25-30, 1967
    - May 30 - June 7, 1967
    - June 7-14, 1967
    - June 14-16, 1967
    - June 16-24, 1967 (Box 9.)
    - June 21 - August 29, 1967
    - July 26 - December 31, 1967
    - August 30 - September 28, 1967
    - October 4 - December 5, 1967
    - December 5, 1967 - February 13, 1968
    - January 1, 1968 - June 14, 1968
    - February 7 - March 15, 1968
    - March 14-23, 1968
    - October 2-21, 1968
    - November 1-20, 1968
    - December 10-26, 1968
  - Appointment books, 1970-1972 (Box 10.)
    - December 31, 1970 - October 21, 1971
    - 1971
    - January - August 1972
- Speeches and Writings, 1958-1971. (Box No. 10.)
  Addresses, research paper, review, clippings, and notes, arranged as listed.
  - Address at Maxwell Air Force Base, concerning the post-war condition of armed services, January 21, 1971 (Box 10.)
  - Address entitled "Opportunities for Young People in Government."
  - Review of a manuscript entitled "Manning the Ramparts," concerning manpower functions in the U.S. Department of Defense
  - "The Role of the Assistant Division Commander in Order to Determine his Most Effective Employment in the Command and Control of a Marine Division," student research project, Marine Corps Schools, Quantico, Virginia, March 1958
  - Clippings on appearances, speeches, and statements of John R. Chaisson
  - Miscellaneous notes
- Subject File, 1941-1973. (Box No. 10-16.)
  Reports, memoranda, lists, clippings, memorabilia, printed matter, and other material, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Biographical File (Box 10.)
  - Carney, Robert B., address to the Naval War College, 1945
  - CBS News special report, "Where We Stand in Vietnam."
  - Commager, Henry S., statement on amnesty
  - Holt, Congressman Joseph F. (Box 11.)
  - Honors and awards
  - Itinerary and map, April 1942-February 1943
  - Memorabilia
  - Military organization
  - Miscellany
  - Orders, 1950-1956
  - Orders, 1962-1970 (Box 12.)
  - Personal file, 1941-1948 (201 military file)
  - Pratt, Albert (Assistant Secretary of the Navy)
  - Pratt, Mrs. Albert, address to the Ohio Federation of Republican Women, 1956
  - Rand Corporation, reports (Box 13.)
    - "Annotated Bibliography on Systems Cost Analysis," by P. A. DonVito
    - "Area Security," by F. J. West, Jr.
    - "A Brief Report from Rural Vietnam," by F. J. West, Jr. and C. Benoit
    - "Conversations with Rural Vietnamese," by Charles Benoit
    - "Enclave: Some U.S. Military Efforts in LyTin District, Quang Tin Province, 1966-1968," by F. J. West, Jr.
    - "An Essay on Vietnamization," by Guy J. Parker
    - "Marine Combined Action Capabilities, the Vietnam Experience," by Bruce C. Allnutt
    - "Military Decision Making and Adaption, The Case of the Air Force Special Air Warfare Wing," by F. J. West, Jr.
    - "Night Pacification Patrolling," by F. J. West, Jr.
    - "Pacification, View from the Provinces," by F. J. West, Jr.
    - "Patrolling," by F. J. West, Jr.
    - "Problems Recognition and Organization Adaptation in a Counterinsurgent Environment," by F. J. West, Jr.
    - "Process of Military Learning and Adaptation, Three Case Studies of Counterforce by Small Units," by F. J. West, Jr.
    - "Systems Analysis and Policy Planning Application in Defense," by E. S. Quade and W. I. Boucher
    - "Tabular Method for Comparing Friendly and Enemy Casualties: A Case Study of Marine Mortalities Resulting from Patrols and Six Offensive Operations in Quang Nam Province," M. E. Arnsten and F. J. West, Jr. (Box 14.)
    - "Techniques of Systems Analysis," by H. Kahn and I. Mann
    - "Unchangeable War," by Brian M. Jenkins
    - "U.S. Fatalities during Vietnamization," by F. J. West, Jr.
    - "U. S. Fatalities during Vietnamization," Part II, by C. Morris and F. J. West, Jr.
    - "Viet Cong Cadres and the Cadre System, A Study of the Main and Local Forces," by Melvin Gurtov
    - "Viet Cong Repression and Its Implications for the Future," by Stephen T. Hosmer
    - "Volunteers for the Viet Cong," by Frank Denton
    - Miscellaneous
  - Sheehy, Maurice S. (Box 15.)
  - Sherman, Forrest P.
  - South Vietnam
    - General file
    - Atrocities
    - Battle for the Khe Sanh
    - Casualties and fatalities
    - Command chronology, 1967
    - Employment of B-52's, 1967
    - Maps
    - Press reporting
      - Coverage of military personnel in I Corps
      - Effects on military capabilities
    - Staff briefings, 1966
    - Strategy and significant details of operational situation, 1967
    - U.S. Marine Corps in Vietnam, summary
    - Vietnamization, 1969
  - Tsingtao, China
    - Expression of gratitude to Major J. R. Chaisson for evacuation, December 1948
    - Station list, Fleet Marine Force, Western Pacific, 1949
  - U.S. Defense Department (Box 16.)
    - Annual report, fiscal 1973
    - Budget, 1957, 1972
    - Manpower functions
    - Manual of Authorities and Responsibilities
    - Summary of report to Secretary James Forrestal by Admiral King, 1945
    - Unification of the War and Navy Departments, summary of report, 1945
  - U.S. Marine Corps
    - Budgetary requirements, 1969, interview with James R. Schlesinger
    - History since 1945
    - Personnel statistics and lists, 1970-1973
  - Westmoreland, William C.
- Correspondence, 1957-1972. (Box No. 16-17.)
  Correspondence, arranged as listed.
  - General file, 1957-1966, 1968-1969, 1971-1972 (Box 16.)
  - General file, January-March 1971
  - General file, May-December 1971 (Box 17.)
  - Abrams, General Creighton W.
  - Bunker, Ambassador Ellsworth
  - Eitan, General R. (Israel)
  - Flemming, Harry S.
  - Gray, Robert
  - Phong, General Tran Thanh (Vietnam)
  - Pratt, Albert
  - Seamans, Robert C., Jr.
  - Shin, Lieutenant General Chae Myung (Korea)
  - Thieu, Nguyen Van
  - Westmoreland, General William C.
- Oral History Transcript, 1975. (Box No. 17.)
  Transcript of an oral history interview with Lieutenant General John R. Chaisson, USMC, by the History and Museums Division of the U.S. Marine Corps, 1975.
  - Transcript of an oral history interview with Lieutenant General John R. Chaisson, USMC, by the History and Museums Division of the U.S. Marine Corps, 1975 (Box 17.)
- Audio-Visual File.
  Photographs, 9 envelopes (280 prints). See also Appendix A, list of sound recordings (tapes)
  - 51 photos of Gen. Chaisson and others in Vietnam, undated (Folder A)
  - 80 Photos of Gen. Chaisson at social and official functions, award presentations and inspections, undated (Folder B-C)
  - 26 photos of Gen. J.R. Chaisson (portraiture), undated (Folder D)
  - 45 photos of J.R. Chaisson and others during World War II and Korean War, undated (Folder E)
  - 10 photos of Gen. Chaisson with important persons, including Gen. William Westmoreland, Amb. Ellsworth Bunker, and J. B. Connally, undated (Folder F)
  - 28 photos of a landing exercise by the 2nd Marine Division, June 1963 (Folder G)
  - 35 photos of J. R. Chaisson and friends near Tsingtao, China, 1948-49 (Folder H)
  - 5 photos of the landing at Peleliu Island, Philippines, September 1944 (Folder I)